

WILFREDO J. MARIN G.

Calle: Priv. Edinburgo N-20 BLVD Condado de Sayavedra, Atizapan de Zaragoza, Mexico. C.P.: 52930

Phone: +55 4661 1984 / 58080631 Email: marinw@gmail.com.

QUALIFICATIONS

Competent MSc. Mechanical Engineer, Strong work ethic. Team-worker. Great interpersonal communication and organizational skills. Able to work under demanding conditions. Experienced with rotating equipment, field operations, instrumentation devices, API Standards. Advanced computer skills. Experienced in software development. Fluent in Spanish & English.

EDUCATION

- Master of Engineering, Machinery & Transportation. In course. UNIVERSIDAD CARLOS III DE MADRID, Madrid, Spain.
- Master of Science Degree, Robotics & Automation. 2011. UNIVERSIDAD CARLOS III DE MADRID, Madrid, Spain.
- Bachelor of Science Degree, Mechanical Engineer 2007. UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL DE VENEZUELA, Caracas, Venezuela.

CAREER SUMMARY

FOSTER WHEELER (Madrid-Spain): since March 2012.

MACHINERY AND SOLID HANDLING DEPARTMENT:

Data sheet, material requisition, technical bid evaluation, drawings and technical documentation control and comments.

NAFTAN, Visbreaker Unit (VBU). Belarus. Fan Material Requisition, Data Sheet and Technical Bid Evaluation.

RBSI Project, Phase II. U11 (ADU) and U12 (VDU) PDVSA PETROLEO, S.A. Barinas (Venezuela). Rotating Equipment Material Requisition and Data Sheet.

Lump Sum Turn Key (LSTK) Proposal RLP 21, U26 (HDS) y U53 (Amines and Sulfur Recovery Unit) "La Pampilla" refinery. Repsol. Ventanilla, Lima. Technical tabulation for inquiry of centrifugal pumps (API).

New (DCU) Coker Unit A – ID&GC stage YPF, La Plata Industrial facilities (YPF). Argentina. Control, comments, monitoring of vendor drawing and detail engineering of centrifugal and dosage pumps (API), inspection for equipment acceptance test.

ALA2INGENIEROS S.L.U. (Madrid - Spain): Aug 2011- Feb 2012.

Software development, hardware technical bid evaluation, technical documents (manual for operation & maintenance), drawings, installation and start-up, vibration analysis test bench.

INGEOSOLUM S.L (Madrid – Spain): Mar 2010- Jul 2011.

(R+D) Department, instrumentation engineer. Machinery mechanical design, technical bid evaluation, technical documents, field test, measurement equipment, supervisory control program code lines.

CARBOSYSTEM (Madrid - Spain): Jan- Dec 2010.

Reverse engineering. High temperature applications, CAD 3D drawings & Layout.

MINISTRY OF ENVIRONMENT (Caracas-Venezuela): Jul 2007- Sep 2009.

Expert consultant. Environmental equipment general division, bathymetry Unit. Data acquisition processing and post-processing. Natural water reservoir hydraulic life estimates.

HYDRAULIC TEST BENCH UCV (Caracas-Venezuela): Jan 2006 – May 2007.

PERFORMANCE AND NPSH TEST FOR CENTRIFUGAL PUMPS. Retrofit. Development and start-up DAQ system for Hydraulic test bed (Hydraulic laboratory).

EDELCA (Puerto Ordaz-Venezuela): Jul 2005- Oct 2005

Expansion Department: Internship & industrial training (hydroelectric energy generation over Caroni River Caruachi dam) on site measurements of different control parameters, creating historical data. Machinery installation training (Turbines: Kaplan, Pumps: Centrifugal) 2005.

TEAM FORMULA SAE UCV (Michigan-USA): 2004 - 2005

SAE COMPETITION std Race car Design, Construction & Test-drive. Bachelor team (Engine). Universities Competition.

IMME UCV "CEBIO" Bioengineering Centre (Caracas-Venezuela): 1999 - 2003

Internship & Industrial training computational codes, development on high level language (fortran), initial models of remodeling bone. Individual Project named "PROMETEO", professor Liber Videla. "Predictor mathematic model of remodeling bone in Long bone under physiologic & pathologic cases". 2000.

SEMINARS AND COURSES

- Control of eolic turbines. UNIVERSIDAD CARLOS III DE MADRID.2009.
- Wearable robots and exoesqueletons. UNIVERSIDAD CARLOS III DE MADRID.2009.
- Processing and analysis of Bathymetric data, CIDIAT institute, Mérida Venezuela. 2007.
- Georeferencing and bathymetry course. INCOSTAS. Caracas Venezuela. 2007.
- DSP processors programming with Lab View Embedded Software, National Instruments Caracas-Venezuela 2007.
- Quality control and maintenance extension course. UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL DE VENEZUELA, Caracas-Venezuela. 2006.
- SAE 2005 World Congress the Society's Centennial. Michigan U.S.A. 2005.
- Days of Investigations (JIFI), Faculty of Engineering, Central University, exhibitor. Caracas-Venezuela. 2000.
- VI Venezuelan Colloquium of Bioengineering, author. Táchira -Venezuela. 2000

SKILLS.

COMPUTATION:

- Catia
- AutoCad.
- SolidWorks.
- SolidEdge

- MatLab.
- LabView.
- Office.

LANGUAGES:

- Spanish (Mother tongue).
- English.

PERSONAL:

- Team worker.
- Personnel management.

- Leadership
- Organizational guidelines.

REFERENCES:

Eng. Antonio Nogales, FOSTER WHEELER IBERIA Madrid-SPAIN (+34) 913.36.28.05

Eng. Wilmer García, SULZER PUMPS (+44) 55 43.507.627

M.Sc.Eng. Liber Videla, IMME Caracas- VENEZUELA (+58) 212.605.17.61